妖女前情提要
Previously on Lost Girl...
你带一个人类到了我们密室
You have brought a human into our chambers.
我特么到底怎么会成黑暗派的
Tell me how I ended up pledged to the dark.
我一点都不知道啊
I don't know jack about it.
无论何时何地 我眼中只有你
Everytime I walk into a room you are all I can look at.
她是关键 肯子 通向我记忆的关键
She is the key, Kenz.To my memories,
寻找Rainer 还有别的什么的关键
to finding Rainer, and who knows what else.
反叛军妄图推翻血之法律
The rebels trying to overturn the blood laws of the Blood King,
为什么
why was that?
他堕落了
He became corrupt.
我在床上找到了这盒子  有你的名字
I found this box on the bed, has your name on it.
这是为啥
What's this about?
时间
Time.
是时候了  我是黑暗派
It's about time.I am Dark.
流浪者把我带走了
I was taken by the Wanderer.
我不知道他是谁 或者和他在一起时
And I don't know who he is or what happened
到底发生了什么 我讨厌这样 因此
when I was with him and I don't like it one bit. So...
我要追查到底
I'm gonna get to the bottom of this once and for all.
谢谢 Kenzi
Thank you, Kenzi.
没问题 Bo-bo
You got it, Bo-bo.
就从这
Starting...
开始
with this.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
Trick你少管
Trick, back off...
Patty Hearst你给我等等 这货不就是那个
Okay, just wait a minute Patty Hearst,is that not the same black smoke
*Patty Hearst 出生富有家庭 1974年被左翼激进组织绑架 后自愿加入该组织*
那个把你从这弄走的黑烟么
that took you from this shithole in the first place?
Kenzi 你要是收藏了一只赫尔鞋  现在你就该
Kenzi, if you have a Hel Shoe in your boot collection, now's time...
我收回  我不给你了！
I'm taking it back... I want it back!
Kenzi 这是她的选择
Kenzi... it's her decision.
谢谢
Thank you.
我同意
I actually agree...
啥
What?!
谢谢
Thank you.
这就是为什么
Which is why...
我们现在应该支持她
...we need to stand by her now
帮助她面对流浪者
and help her face this Wanderer.
团结起来
Together...
没错 可是
Yes, but...
我觉得我特么就跟在托儿所似的
I feel like I'm in a room full of children.
大家帮帮忙
Guys! Please!
她极可能再次被抓
she could be taken, again
或者消失  可不见得能再次回来
Lost. And we might not get her back this time.
大家都闭嘴
Damn it, people.
她要是打开那个瓶子 她还可以
- If she opens that jar, she could also...
没门！
-Not happening!
Kenzi你把那个还我
- Kenzi! You give that back now.
不 我可不要眼睁睁看着你再被抓走
No, I'm not gonna sit back and have you taken again.
我说了还给我！
I said give it back!
啊！
Eugh!
Isabeau!
你们还不明白我的处境吗？
Don't you see what is happening to me?
被蒙在鼓里已经把我搞疯了
Not knowing is driving me crazy.
对不住 可这到头了
I'm sorry.But this has to end now...
哦 尼玛
Oh, what the hell.
啊
Ah.
Trick大爷您没事吧
Trickster you okay?
大哥您是敌是友
Friend or foe, pal?
看你那表情我觉得你大概想的是敌人吧
By the looks of you though I'd say you were betting on foe.
本作品片源来自互联网，仅供个人影视制作学习交流之用
任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途
挪威金毛的胡须最有爱了字幕组  ╮(╯▽╰)╭
英文字幕：来自互联网
翻译：Neffititi 骷髅头正宫_K
校对：潜行的五 Momo酱各种大爱
压制：joy
发布：百度贴吧Tamsin后援群
资源下载请关注瓦尔基里字幕组官方微博
4x09 - Destiny's Child
我叫Hugin 是流浪者的仆从
My name is Hugin and I am the most humble servant of the Wanderer.
就现在来说
And for the time being...
我不是来挑事的
I mean you no harm.
天  你真是可爱
My. My. Aren't you a pretty little thing.
谢谢
Thanks.
我是 或曾经是  流浪者的思想
I am, or at least have been, the Wanderer's thought.
一个穿越不同平面的容器
A vessel really traveling from plane to plane gathering
搜集某个妹子的信息
information about certain women...
我们见过 是么
We've met. Haven't we?
是的
Yes.
我兄弟  Munin和我把你
My brother, Munin and I took you from this…
*Hugin和Munin 北欧神话中奥丁的两只乌鸦 意为思想和记忆*
从这里带走去了火车上
... shithole and brought you to his train.
我们父亲的火车 如假包换
Our father's train. So it is written ... so it is said.
父亲？
Father?
是的 流浪者是个伟大的人
Yes. The Wanderer is a great man.
是众人之父
And a father to many.
他要真这么伟大 干吗不敢露面
If he's such a great man why doesn't he show his face?
为什么要用谎言和戏剧来伪装自己
Why does he hide behind cheap lies and theatrics?
恩 我真的不知道
Hmm. I really don't know.
但也许你能告诉我为什么血王
But perhaps you could tell me why the Blood King
会躲在一个酒吧的吧台后面
has to hide behind a bar at a local watering hole?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
得了吧亲爱的
Oh, dear.
你的面瘫脸太挫了 不过啥时候不都这样吗
Your poker face is lousy. But then again, it always was.
我的王
My liege.
嘿！
Hey!
集中精力  我要回到那火车上
Focus. I need to get back on that train.
艾玛谁不想啊
Well join the club.
它在哪
Where is it?
我毫不知情
I haven't the foggiest.
扯淡
Bullshit!
我向你保证 我不撒谎
I assure you. I do not lie.
我兄弟Munin把我关进了瓶子
My brother Munin trapped me in that jar soon as you
就在你上车后  它去了哪 我不知道
got on that train.  Where it is now, I know not.
你兄弟不喜欢你的幽默？
Brother didn't like your jokes?
不喜欢我的老婆不是他的
Didn't like the fact my wife wasn't his.
啊 那他们现在在哪  渡蜜月吗
Ah. So where are they now? Honeymoon?
他做梦吧
One could only hope.
我要回去  现在
I need back to get back there. Now.
我会帮助你
and I will help you
但你得帮我解决我那背后捅了我一刀的兄弟
But only if you help me take revenge on my back-stabbing brother
和我那讨厌的老婆
and that repulsive quim I used to call my wife.
Munin知道火车在哪
Munin will know the location of the train.
等你呢兄弟
Waitin' on you pal.
好 走你
Yeah, let's go.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
哦不行不行
Oh, no, no, no.
要么我和你 要么没人走
We go alone or we don't go at all.
办不到
That's not gonna work for us.
她去哪我们就去哪
Where she goes, we go.
那我就走了
Then I will take my leave.
什么？别！等等！
What? No! Wait!
等一下
Just wait.
我爱你们两个  真的很爱
I love you both. So much.
但现在我需要你们看我离开
But right now I need you to watch me walk away...
因为必须如此
because I have to do this.
从来不会简单点  是吧
It's never gonna get easier, is it?
我准备好了
I'm ready
非常好
Excellent.
顺便说下 我们回到火车上
Oh, and by the way, when we get on the train...
我要发现你是我老板的敌人
if I find out you're an enemy of my employer
我可要按他的意思鞭挞你
I will flay you to his liking.
哦 我就知道
Oh! I knew it!
很高兴认识你们 白了
So nice meeting you all.Ta!
我错过了啥
What did I miss?
你怎么去了这么久
What took you so long?
我去搞我的科学装备了
I was getting my science stuff...
你有你的武器  你的狼性
You got your weapons, and your wolf,
我有我的大脑  我们还都有
and I've got my brains and we both have...
我们这就出发去救我们的妹子吧
Let's just go get our girl. Ok?
你是否……
You're um...
我准备好要痛扁一群乌鸦 没错
I am ready to kick some Crow ass. Yes.
我本来要说可怕 不过也行
I was going to say terrifying but yeah, that'll do.
给你
Here.
我知道你有头脑 有科学
I know you have your brains and your science,
但是你多拿把刀我会放心得多
but it would make me feel a lot better if you also had a knife.
谢谢你 Dyson
Thank you, Dyson.
不用谢 Lewis医生
You're welcome, Dr. Lewis.
你知道吗 我不知道我能不能办到
You know? I'm not sure if I could either.
什么
What?
做选择
Choose.
我能
I could.
是吗
Yeah...
我们出发吧
Let's do this.
Trick大爷 你为什么对着那只朦胧的讨厌的帅气的乌鸦
Trickster, why are you PMS'ing over that gorgeous,
做着来大姨妈一样的表情？
smoky, crowy, ass-face, hot, jerk?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what your talking about.
我们不相信你
We don't believe you.
恕我直言  你不是曾经给流浪者打工吗
I'm sorry, weren't you once an employee of the Wanderer?
恩 我们不是来谈Tamsin的
Eh, eh, eh, we're not here to talk about Tamsin!
行吗？
Okay?
我得走了
I have to go...
别这样 你就是我们的度娘 你肯定知道什么
Look, come on, you're our Trickipedia! You gotta know something.
你可是尤达大师  用你的原力告诉我们答案吧！
You're freakin' Yoda. Force must use to problem answer find!
*Yoda 星球大战中主角的导师*
对吧
Yes?
我没时间和你们搞这
- I don't have time for this.
你没时间？
Oh, I'm sorry, you don't have time?
真不好意思  可你什么都没干
I'm sorry, but you have not done one thing
流浪者把Bo抓走了 你什么也没干
to help Bo since the Wanderer took her!
我要以前的那个Trick
I want the old Trick back.
那个无事不晓 悉心呵护大家的老头
The one that knows things and cares about people
还有你怎么可能不知道究竟是怎么回事
and why haven't you figured this out yet?!
我才没时间给一个人类和一个低等生命
I don't have time to explain myself to a human...
解释我的人生
and a lowlife...
对不起  求你们了 别再问了行吗
I'm sorry... just leave it be. I'm begging you.
他真是有什么秘密 对吧
He really is hiding something. Isn't he?
看起来确实
Certainly looks that way.
那我们也只剩一件事可做了
Well, there's only one thing left to do.
在他床上拉屎
Take a dump on his bed.
不是！我想说……恶心！
No! I was gonna say... Ew!
我错了 那你想怎么样
I'm sorry. What do you wanna do?
我们来翻箱倒柜
Snoop.Look around his place...
不是 你懂的
- not... you know.
好吧 我们来窥探一番
- Okay, we'll snoop.
好的
Okay...
请小心别踩到坟墓上
Please be careful not to step on top of the graves.
这是异种的坟场
This is a Fae burial ground.
意思是？
Meaning?
意思是你只要轻轻一碰
Meaning you put so much as a pinky on top of one of the sacred plots
就会被列维坦给吸去Irkalla了
and you'll be sucked down to Irkalla by the Leviathan.
*Leviathan 圣经中盘踞海洋的怪物 原形来自鲸鱼 鳄鱼或蛇*
Irkalla?
*巴比伦神话中的地狱*
是的 又称地狱  或者叫阴间
Yes. Some call it hell, some call it the netherworld,
我要叫它法国
I call it France.
这笑话在英国可是满堂彩
Hm. Usually kills in Britain.
我们来这干嘛  Hugin
What are we doing here, Hugin?
我和我兄弟曾经住在这
My brother and I used to live here.
我们乌鸦在死人周围比较舒服
We Crows are always more comfortable around death,
在活人和死人的世界间穿梭
travelling as we do between the living world and the afterlife.
对我们来说 你懂  很有家的感觉
To us, you know, it's quite homey.
哦 我想可能这里确实……不 这地方挫爆了
Well, I guess it does have a certain...No, this place sucks.
我们还是完成任务就走吧
Let's just get what we came for and get out of here.
你好 兄弟
Hello, brother.
你好你好你好
'Allo, 'allo, allo!
真是惊喜啊
What a pleasant surprise.
惊喜？真的？
Pleasant? Really?
是的 惊喜
Yeah. Pleasant.
就跟你被狗吃 或者因为上课不听话
Like being eaten by dogs or having your knuckles
被修女敲打指关节
rapped by a nun for horsin' about in class.
辣么喜悦
That kind of pleasant.
我兄弟真是个诗人
He's a poet, my brother.
蠢如狗屎  但真是个诗人
Dumb as dog shite...but a poet none-the-less.
行吗
Shall we?
哦 没问题 好的
Oh, yes, please.
啊 啊 啊
Caw, caw, caw!
一是悲伤
One for sorrow.
*出自童谣 原歌中为喜鹊 传入北美地区后改为乌鸦 此处歌词有改动*
二是欢乐
Two for mirth
三是葬礼
Three for a funeral.
四是诞生
Four for birth.
五是天堂
Five for heaven.
六是地狱
Six for hell.
七是恶魔  他自己
And seven is the devil...his own self.
太好了
Excellent.
我就喜欢奇数
'Cause I like them odds.
你好 Hugin我的亲亲小宝贝
Hello, Hugin.My little treasure.
你好亲爱的  很高兴见到你
Hello, darling. So nice to see you.
真不想跟你形容吃你胸中的心脏
Can't tell you how much I'm going to enjoy eating
会是多么愉悦的一件事
the heart right out of your chest.
我俩在一起的时候你要是擅长吃某些东西
If you had been better at eating certain things when we were together
我也不会抛弃你转投你兄弟的怀抱了
I never would have left you for your brother.
不难看出家里谁热情似火
Not hard to see who got the passion in that family.
是Munin 他情热如火
It's Munin.He got the passion.
我猜猜  你老婆
Let me guess.The wife?
对啊 她很可爱吧
Yeah.Isn't she a peach.
我们要跑吗
Shall we run?
为毛不呢
Why not?
啊
Ergh!
书 旧书
Books. Old books.
一堆旧书  更旧的书
More old books... older than the other old books.
哦
Oooh.
看这个  又是本旧书
Look at this. It's another old book that is...
空白的
blank.
你说什么
What did you say?
旧书？还是更旧的书？
What about the books? Or the more old books?
空白的那个
About the blank.
对 这里这本
Yeah. This one here.
空白  什么也没
Empty. Nothing doing.
饿滴神呀 就是这了
Oh my god. This is it.
是啥
What?
这就是我们作甚要酱紫
This is what we have to do.
哦你说在上面画丁丁大全吗
Oh like, you mean ...draw weird dicks in there.
不  听着 在Bo跟她妈 Aife 打完后
No. Look, after Bo's fight with her mother... with Aife...
我在这找到了人事不省的Trick
I found Trick passed out down here.
濒临死亡  他在这书上写东西
Near death. He was writing in this book.
用他自己的血
With his own blood.
他刺穿血管 书写未来 为了救Bo
He opened his veins and rewrote the future to save Bo.
真沉重
Heavy.
是啊 真的
Yeah. Real heavy.
引出了Garuda相关的一系列事
It unleashed a shitstorm by the name of the Garuda.
是你之前的事
It's before your time.
好吧  但你不觉得乱搞血书
Okay! But don't you think messing with Blood writings
就算对我们来说也是个馊主意吗
is a bad idea? Even for us.
不 Trick对乌鸦烟雾的反应
No, the way Trick reacted Crow's smoke. What it did to him.
我敢说这事他绝对有份
I have a feeling in my gut that he's wrapped up in all this.
他以前也对Bo有所保留过
He has kept things from Bo before.
所以我觉得答案在这书里 在他的过去
So I think that the answers lie in this book. In his past.
或者未来吧
Or his future I guess.
可是肯子
- But, Kenz...
听着 Tammy Bo一直都在保护我
Look, Bo's always had my back, Tammy.
她救过我无数次
She has saved my life countless times.
甚至我俩还没互相认识的时候
Even from the minute she didn't know me.
我觉得现在该换我了 你懂吗
I think it's time I had hers. You know?
好吧  算我一个
Okay. I'm in.
接下来呢
What next?
恩我们得要点Trick的血
Well, we uh need some of Trick's blood.
哦太好了 我还以为会很难
Oh, well that's good. 'Cause I thought it was gonna be difficult.
恩他说过以前他会在墨水瓶里放一些
Yeah. He told me back in the day he would store his
他的血  以便随时书写
blood in an ink well... ready to write at a moments notice.
你觉得墨水瓶在这里？
You think it's in here?
恩我们的Trick可是个行为固定的人
Well he's a creature of habit, our Trick.
肯定在这里  而且就我所知
It is definitely in here. And knowing him...
要找到绝对不是件容易 安全的事
it's not going to be easy or safe to find.
太好了
Great.
恩
Yeah.
Fitzy 是你吗
Fitzy.Is that you?
*Fitzy Fitzpatrick的昵称*
Dao ming  见到你真惊讶
Dao-ming. What a nice surprise.
你真想站那骗一个甪端吗
Are you really going to stand there and lie to a Luduan?
*甪端 中国传说生物 可知事实*
我想不了  我在找你姐姐
I suppose not.I'm looking for your sister.
哦  你是要来和她复合？
Oh? Have you come to win her back?
你知道我为什么来
You know why I'm here.
Fitzy 我可不会读心术
I'm not a mind reader, Fitzy...
我不过是个能探知真相的异种罢了
just a simple Fae that can find the truth.
即使是
Even in the most...
最强大的敌人
formidable of opponents.
我再也不是什么贵族了
I no longer live as Royalty.
我是说男人 都是骗子
I meant men. Liars.
你们每个人都是
Every last one of you.
Ming我需要答案
I need answers, Ming. Now.
对不起  Wai Lin不在
So sorry, Wai Lin is away helping
*Wai Lin 2x13中的甪端 让Dyson发现他不可能再爱上别人的那位*
她去参与很重要的国际谈判了
with some very important international negotiations.
她又回联合国了
She's back at the UN?
是非死不可啦
Facebook.
世界变化之大呀 我能怎么说呢  酒保大大
The world has changed. What can I say, Barkeep?
帮我
Help me.
才不要
No.
为什么
Why?
因为人家不想嘛
Because I don't feel like it.
再说了 你以前也寻找答案
Besides, you've wanted answers before.
可不好说是不是真的帮了你
Not sure it did you much good.
有段回忆
There's a memory.
被某个很强大的人屏蔽了
It has been blocked by someone very powerful.
你觉得我要是强迫你吐露真相
And you think if I force you to tell the truth...
那段回忆就会探出头走向光明？
this memory will just poke its little head back into the light?
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
我有钱
I have money...
在你对我家人做过的那些事后 我为什么还要帮你
Why should I help you after everything you've done to my family?!
因为 你恨那个屏蔽这段记忆的人
Because. You hate the person who's blocked this memory.
那是谁
And who might that be?
我  我觉得我自己屏蔽了自己的记忆
Me.I think I did this to myself.
这 听起来可有趣得很
Now... this is interesting.
不用魔法草药吗 Ming
No magic herbs, Ming?
我还以为它们帮助甪端进入真实之域
I thought they helped you Luduan's engage the realm of truth.
我呸
Pfft.
过时的把戏  现在不值一提了
Antiquated parlor tricks. Hardly worth it these days.
你没见过我姐姐的牙齿吗
Have you seen my sisters teeth?
我会帮你
I will help.
谢谢
Thank you.
有个条件
On one condition.
你说
Name it.
我可以问你任何问题
I get to ask you any question I want...
你必须告诉我真相
and you must let me get the truth ...
不管再痛苦
no matter how painful.
好吧
Fine.
为了我孙女  我给你我的血誓
For my granddaughter's safety... I give you ... my blood oath.
很好  第一个问题
Excellent. First question
问吧
Shoot.
你为什么选我姐姐不选我
Why did you pick my sister over me?
哦天啊
Oh boy.
好吧 看来我们得用老法子
Ok. Looks like we're gonna have to do this
用拳头决定胜负
the old fashioned way and fight our way out.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
淫妖  我生来就准备好了
Succubus.I was born ready.
哇  你干嘛
Whoa! What are you doing?
对不起
I'm sorry.
自从我父亲
But, ever since my father...
那个流浪的人！
He who Wanders!
自从那个流浪的人
Ever since, he who Wanders,
把我封进瓶子 你懂  我就开始恨他了
banished me to that jar, well you know, I've kind of grown to hate him.
那么你和你老婆
So, you and the wife ...
非常相爱
Very much in love I'm afraid.
你老板把你搞得生不如死
Your boss is the one who screwed you over.
关老娘什么事
What does this have to do with me?
你似乎是我前任老板的心头好
It seems you are of particular interest to our decaying former employer.
所以我觉得我跟我兄弟可以
So I thought my brother and I...
割你的喉咙
Would slit your throat.
哦 那你们干嘛这么神叨叨的
Oh.So why the charade?
就酱杀一个人一点也不好玩
Well, it's hardly any fun  killing someone outright...
不刺激 没有追逐 就好像
No thrill? No chase? It'd be like the King,
国王直接射杀一只狐狸一样
just shooting the fox in the head point blank.
那有什么可乐的
Where's the fun in that?
最好是放出猎犬 来场游戏
Better to release the hounds. And make a game of it.
对啊 再说
Yeah and besides.
我最爱看猎物发现被骗后
I do like seeing the expression change…
脸上的表情
when they know they've just been double-crossed.
真是让我血液沸腾啊
Mmm... really gets the blood pumping.
连心脏都温暖起来了
It warms the cockles of my heart.
那等我让你失望的时候
Well, then I'll enjoy seeing the looks on your faces
我也要享受下你脸上的表情
when I disappoint you.
哦
Oh.
你预备怎么样呢  恩？
And how exactly is that going to happen, eh?
你被困住了 包围了
You're trapped. Surrounded.
是啊 你没说错
Yeah, you're right.
但今天没人能割我的喉咙 哪天也不行
But nobody is slitting my throat today ... or any time soon.
恩 没想到诶
Hmm...I did not see that coming.
这可不妙
Well that sucked.
啊
Ah.
谁在那
Who's there?
谁在那？
既棕且蓝
Both brown and blue.
喂
Hello?
既棕且蓝！
Both brown and blue!
强大又温柔
Strong yet gentle...
妹子 我可没时间和你瞎耗
I don't have time for games, Lady.
贞洁又放荡
Virtuous yet lustful!
你给我出来
Show yourself!
我知道你是谁
I know you!
I know you.
我确实很受欢迎 我猜猜
I am pretty popular these days. Let me guess.
列维坦？
The Leviathan?
你的灵魂
Your soul...
你特么作甚
What the hell?
你从哪得到那标记的
Where did you get that mark!?
你是说我胸口的掌印吗
Oh you mean the hand hickey on my chest?
火车的上的某人 趁我喝多了
Some guy on a train ...I had a lot to drink ...
更重要的是
the more important question is
这地方的门在哪 大妈
where the hell is the door to this place,lady?
我找那个标记找了600年了
I have been searching for that mark for six hundred years.
它应该是我的 他们不给我
It was supposed to me mine. They kept it from me.
我要标记！我需要它！
I want it!I need it!
你需要这个标记
You want and need this mark.
老娘还需要回去那个坟场呢
I want and need back to that graveyard.
孩子 没人能从这出去
No one ever leaves here,child.
从来没人出去
No one has ever left.
给我那个标记
Now give me that mark!
你真想要？
You want it?
你来拿啊 来啊
Come and get it.
我本来也想不废话了直接打一架吧
I'd just as soon stop screwing around and fight for it anyway.
那还比较合我胃口
It's a little more my style.
很好
Excellent.
那就猜谜游戏吧
A game of riddles then it is.
谜语？
Riddles?
地狱里没有愤怒的小鸟吗
There's no Angry Birds in Irkalla?
你同意吗
Do you agree?
我看你也不接受讨价还价
I don't suppose you'd care to haggle.
你同意吗
Do you agree?!
同意
Yes.
是的我同意
Yes, I agree.
太好了
Excellent.
你第一次用你的血改变历史是什么时候
When did you first use your blood to change history?
我……不记得了……
I don't...I don't remember...
达姆甘地震 达姆甘首领们揭竿而起
The Damghan Earthquake.The Damghan leaders became defiant…
*达姆甘地震 发生于公元856年伊朗达姆甘 震级7.9级 20万人死亡*
他们不守规矩 自然要受些惩罚
and unruly...they needed to be taught a lesson.
地震死了多少人
How many did it kill?
超过20万人 是场大屠杀
Over 200,000 souls.It was a massacre.
可那阻止了一场更大的悲剧 种族清洗
But it prevented a larger massacre. A genocide ...
你从地球上消灭了多少灵魂
How many souls have you wiped from this Earth?
成百上千万 可是
Millions! But...
你最爱的是谁
Who do you love most?
Isabeau 你知道的
Isabeau.You know that.
说真话！
Tell me the truth!
我是
I am...
究竟是谁
Who?
我 我才是这世界的第一人
Me! I am the first son of this Earth.
我才是那个该被膜拜的人
I am the one to be worshipped!
我 我不想继续了
I'm... I'm not going to continue.
Ming求你了
Ming, please.
你封锁的记忆不想出来
Whatever is buried in there does not want to come out.
可是
But...
我怕啊 Fitzy
I am frightened,Fitzy.
我怕真相 怕它会如何影响我们
I'm frightened of what it could be.What it could mean...for all of us.
Bo有生命危险 她是我唯一的后人了
Bo's life is in danger. She's all I have left of my line.
Ming 你必须继续 我求你了
Ming,you have to continue,please.I beg of you.
那好吧
So be it.
我暗如黑夜 明如白昼
I am black as night and as bright as day
寒如早春 暖如初夏
as cold as March and as warm as May.
我是什么
What am I?
你是 呃
You're um...
对 我是什么
Yes,what am I?
雾
Fog?
你是雾 对吗 雾就是答案
You're fog, right? That's the answer.
啊！
Eugh!
该你了公主殿下
Your turn,Princess.
看来你有点输不起啊小列
Oh,not big on losing huh, Levi?
游戏还没结束呢 还有别那么叫我
The game is not over yet. And don't call me that.
快点
Go!
好的好的 我来说
OK,OK,I'm going.
不在这啊
It's not here.
接着找
Keep looking.
我们找了好久了 这里没有
We've been looking for hours.It's not here.
好恶心呀 Tamsin
Gross,Tamsin!
是地板的声音啦
It was the floor!
那是啥
What is that?
不可能吧
This can't be.
神马
What?!
这是玉手箱
It's a Tametebako.
*日式折纸，呈多边形，可以从任何一面打开，但打开后很难复原*
鱼香肉丝
A tomato-bacon!
美味
Yum!
不是啦
Ah,no.
这是个日式折叠盒
This is a Japanese folding box.
这些符号 可是这不科学
These markings ...but this is impossible.
给姐解释一下 金毛酱
Fill a brother in, Tam-tam.
15世纪，日本渔人浦島太郎遇见过一只乌龟
In fifth century Japan a fisherman,Urashima Taro,met a turtle...
*浦島太郎 日本传说中曾去往龙宫 得到宝盒 打开后一夜白头死去*
姐也遇见过好多乌龟
I've met turtles.
不 那只乌龟是龙王被诅咒的女儿
No.This turtle was the cursed daughter of the Emperor.
她给了渔人一个神秘的盒子 如果我没搞错的的话
She gave the fisherman a magical box...if I'm not mistaken...
这就是那个神秘盒子
it is this magical box.
那种可以许个愿的神秘盒？
Like,make a wish,magical box?
还是像大姨妈来晚了的惊喜神秘盒
Or just like have a late period, magical box?
这货可以保护你 但是想都别想打开它
Like protect you from evil but don't you dare open it
除非你知道盒子的组成机关
unless you know the combination magical box.
你可以从任何一面打开它 但是打开盒子的组合是无穷无尽的
It opens from all sides.But the combinations are endless.
如果我是血圣的话
Hm.Well if I was the Blood King...
我会把我的血藏这里面 妥妥的
This is where I'd hide my blood? Yeah.
塔塔 这可能会是我俩做过的
Tammy, this may be the single
最不负责，最可怕的事了
most irresponsible/frightening thing we've ever done.
比上次，只是因为你大姨妈痛
More irresponsible than the time we snuck into the Fae Veterans hospital switched charts
我们就跑到异种退役兵医院偷图表还要不负责任？
Because you were having period cramps...
嘘 我们说好不提这个的 不过没错
Shh! We said we would never talk of that again.But,yes!
那我们必须打开它咯
Let's totally do it.
同意
Agreed!
我快厌倦你的拖延症了公主
I grow weary of your stalling, princess.
我说了不要叫人家公主 而且我才没有拖延症呢
I said stop calling me that. And, I'm not stalling...
我只是好久没猜谜了
I just haven't played a lot of riddle games.
好吧 他们并不是一个事物
That's all.They're not really a thing.
他们很复古 大概吧
They're kind of old fashioned...sort of like
反正都是关于你自己的
everything about you.
别讽刺我
Don't you mock me!
好好
Yeah,yeah...
好 我想起一个了
Ok,I've got one.
伊人聪敏
She's brilliant.
君子强健
He's strong.
美人命如蝼蚁 髦士生且悠长
Her life is little...his life is long...
其心至纯
both loves are pure...
其爱至真
both loves are true...
问君如吾
if you were I ...
谁当为良人
who would you choose?
谁当为善偶
Who would I choose?
啥 请说普通话
What...what do you mean?
选择 就是做选择咯
Choose?As in choice?
这是你的花招
This is a trick!
哎大姐啊
Oh,Lady...
这事儿烦死了 烦得要死
it is annoying hell...a times...
让人感情倍受折磨 不过这要是个阴谋的话
it is emotionally crippling.But if it's a trick?
那上面某些人可太有幽默感了
Then someone up there has quite the sense of humour.
现在 回答我的谜语小列
Now,answer the riddle,Levi.
这不公平
This isn't fair!
咋了 你这是要哭的节奏
What,you're gonna cry?
噢
Oh!
我警告你
I am warning you...
回答我的问题
Answer it!
男人 他活得更长
The man! He will live longer...
这是你的最终答案了
Final answer?
等下 啊
No...wait.Um...
啊
Ah...Um...
女人 对 你爱她
The woman.Uh,yes,you love her.
你用她的人性做盾牌
You wear her humanity like a shield.
那么我们就选女人了小列
So we're stickin with the woman,Levi?
不 等等 男人
No,um,wait uh...the man.
对 你渴望力量 男人
Yes, you crave strength. The man.
我回答男人
I answer the man.
啊你这混蛋
Oh! Damn you!
不好意思 太杯具了 现在把我送回去 猪扒女
Too bad,so sad. Now send me back up,fish fingers.
答案是女人吗 我早该知道
Was it the woman?I must know.
我还希望你告诉我呢
Hey,I was kind of hoping you could tell me
不过目前为止 我也不知道答案
because as far as I know...there is no answer.
你作弊
You cheated!
没有呀 这是Bo式谜语
Uh, no. I Bo'd it.
而且有商标注册的哦
And yes,that is trademarked.
你会为你所做的事付出代价的
I will make you pay for this.
你干嘛那么乖戾
Why are you so grumpy?
我会给你送点点心下来的 我保证
I'll send you down a snack, I promise.
现在上去
Now up!
很好
Very well.
什么事那么好笑 小列
Something funny,Levi?
我很快就会再见到你了 很快
I will be seeing you again,soon enough.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你深深爱着的一个人 很快就会死去
Someone you love very much...will soon be dead.
什么
What!?
等等 谁
Wait!? Who!?
Munin
Munin?
Hugin什么事
Yes, Hugin?
等流浪者和他的小可怜一起掉进深渊
What part of being rich will you like best once The Wanderer
我们搜刮他藏起来的财富
has fallen into the abyss with his pathetic choochoo
变得有钱以后 你最想干什么
and we collect all of his riches we've hidden about the world?
让我想想
Well, I will tell you, see...
我的灵魂告诉我 统治世界
my soul is saying world domination ...
但是我内心深处有一个地方在说
but there are other parts of me that are saying...
每晚换个女人
a different woman every night!
啊
Agh!
Ah!
捉住她
Get her!
哇 哥怎么没预见这事
Whoa. I did not see that coming!
哼
Hmm.
啊
Ahhh!
Ah.
啊
Argh!
哇 运气不太好呀
Whoa. That was a bit bad luck, wasn't it?
你懂什么 我们三对一
Well, what do you know?  Three for a girl.
三个对一个女孩 是谁 哦 太杯具了
Yeah. Three for a girl...who is, um, sadly...
你又处于劣势了哦
Outnumbered once again.
我可没有那么确定
I wouldn't be so sure.
快跑 小心脚下
Run! Watch your step!
我见过比这样结束婚姻更糟的
Oh... well, I've seen marriages end in worse ways.
你怎么能够
How did you, uh...
乌鸦的恶臭
The stench of Crow.
追寻起来很简单
Easy enough to track.
啊你看 我真没预见到这个 我发誓
Well, uh... see, I really did not see that coming, I swear.
闭嘴 Munin
Oh, shut up, Munin!
啥都没有
Here goes nothing.
好吧
Okay.
Trick古里古怪的
Trick is really weird.
噢
Oh.
你想来开下一个吗
Do you want to open the next one?
好吧好吧 别这么暴力嘛
Alright, alright. There's no need to get violent.
闭嘴 否则我撕开你的喉咙
Shut it or I'll tear your throat out.
我会给你们俩注射满满的异种性病病毒
And I'll pump you both so full of Fae STD's
你制造下一代的东西马上就会掉下来
your little egg fertilizers will drop right off.
这太可怕了
Wow, that's intense.
太过了
Too much?
不 很好
No, it's good.
你得承认 兄弟 他们确实有点假威风
You have to admit brother. They do have a certain panache.
我真该让妈妈杀掉你
I should have let mother kill you.
好了舒克 贝塔
Okay.Heckle. Jeckle.
我必须回到那个火车上 现在
I need to get back on that train. Now.
啊 背叛这个东西 意味着
Yeah well, the thing about betrayal is
你一旦背叛了人 他们就不再喜大普奔
once you betrayed someone they hardly welcome you
伸开双手欢迎你了
back into their lives with open arms.
除非是伸开的双手拿着剑
You know...unless there's a sword in each one.
说的对 我们回到火车上的话 我们死定了
Very good point. If we get back on that train... we're dead.
所以你就用最坏的方式处置我们吧
So you just might as well do your worst.
我们最坏的处罚 Dyson 你最坏的处罚是什么
Oh, our worst, huh? Dyson ... what would your worst be?
我可以把他们开膛
I could disembowel them...let them swim around in
让他们在自己的内脏里游会儿泳 挺痛的
their own entrails for a little while. That's painful.
极其痛苦
Ouf. Excruciating.
Lauren呢
Lauren?
我可以给他们注射异种大苍蝇的幼虫
Well I could inject them with the larvae of a Fae Bot Fly.
小虫子们会占据他们的中央神经系统
Little bugger would take over their central nervous system...
让他们对自己作出各种恐怖的事情
make them do all sorts of horrible things to themselves.
你懂啦 自残 内脏流血
You know, self-mutilation...internal bleeding...
我喜欢
Mmm, I like that one.
好吧好吧 我们懂了
Oh... alright. Alright.  We get the picture.
一个提议
A proposition.
我们听着呢
We're all ears.
我兄弟和我会让你上火车
My brother and I will get you on that train...
如果你保证一旦你双脚踏上火车地板
If you promise to let us leave as soon as your...
就让我们离开
Feet touch the rotting floor.
成交 走吧
Deal. Lets go.
Bo 不要
Bo, no.
你不可以就这样把你的后宫留在这里啊
You can't just leave us here.
爱妃们 我告诉你了 这事我得自己去做
Guys, I told you. I need to do this on my own.
我们是你的家人
We are your family
你这个奇怪的
Your weird...
复杂的
complicated...
完全功能不调的家人
Completely dysfunctional family ...
可是我们还是你的家人
But we are your family nonetheless.
你们是我的亲人
You are my family.
我是这世界上最幸运的女孩
And I'm the luckiest girl in the whole world.
这也是为什么 我不能让你们为我冒险
Which is why I can not let you risk your lives for me.
Bo
Bo...
接飞吻吧  爱人 飞吧
Catch, lover. Fly.
你知道那个吻是给我的吧
You know that kiss was for me, right?
你这么说一千遍就会成真似的
Yeah, you just keep telling yourself that.
你做过的最恶劣的事情是什么
What is the worst thing you've ever done?
我 我不记得了
I don't... I don't remember...
我
I...
告诉我
Tell me!
你这滑稽 低级 下贱的异种
You ridiculous, cheap, low-born Fae.
你知道我有多强大吗
Do you have any idea how powerful I am?
我现在就可以割开我的血管
I could open my veins right now
把你写出历史
and write you out of history for good...
就像我对Rainer做的
Like I did Rainer!
啊
Agh.
是那样的 我记起来了
That's it. I remember.
我记起来流浪者是谁了
I remember who the Wanderer is.
他是怎么变成现在这样的
How he came to be what he is now.
我知道为什么我没有……因为我……
I know why I haven't been trying to...It's because I...
是我吗 是我干的吗
Did I do this? Did I do this to...
都是我干的 是吗
I created all of this, didn't I?
好悲伤啊Fitzy
So sad, Fitzy.
你多努力的想要放弃你的能力
You've tried so hard to walk away from your power.
为了做对事情
To make things right.
但说到底 过去终究会找上你 就算你
But in the end, the past will always find a way. Even you.
就算你是全能的血王
Even the all-powerful Blood King,
就算你的能力如同诅咒般强大
even your power is a curse.
就算你也无法摆脱命运的掌控
Even you cannot escape fate.
你特么到底觉得哪好笑了
What in the world could be funny at a moment like this?
就算你有能力改变未来
With all of your ability to change the future,
不管你做什么 你始终无法
no matter what you do, you are still powerless
改变你的本性
to change your nature.
我得去找Bo 我要警告她
I have to find Bo.I have to warn her.
我会告诉我姐你来过的 Fitzy
I will tell my sister you come by, Fitzy.
事情真的严肃起来了
Shit just got real.
我们怎么办
What do we do?
涂指甲吧
Finger paint.
肯子
Kenz!
伦家开个玩笑嘛,，你有更好的主意吗
I'm only half kidding.Do you have a better idea?
没
No.
啊 小心要爆了
Ah!  Fire in the hole!
好吧
Okay.
啊  恩
Uh...Eugh.
没用啊
It's not working!
好吧
Okay.
可能得Trick自己写吧  或者比如
Maybe trick needs to write in it. Or, uh...
像是他写过的人之类的 对不起啊肯子
Someone Trick has written about. I'm sorry Kenz.
啊 Kenzi
Ah, Kenzi!
这是怎么回事
What's happening?
我不知道
I don't know.
Tamsin放手啊
Tamsin let go!
啊 我放不开啊！
Agh! I can't!
我必须带走他的灵魂 它是我的
I must take his soul. It belongs to me.
哦天啊
Oh boy.
不
No.
但这是战士的灵魂
But this is a warrior's soul.
我必须将其带走 这是我的使命
I must take it.  It is my purpose.
不
No.
你知道的 血王  他战败了
You know this, Blood King. He has fallen in battle
我必须要将他带往英灵殿的战士之厅
and I must take him to the Einherjar in Valhalla.
这是已经写好的
It is written.
写好的？ 写好的？
Written? Written?
要不是我写的 能有多重要
If it wasn't written by me then what importance could it have?
你知道会发生什么
But you know what will happen...
你太看得起你自己了 秃鹫
You overstate your importance, Vulture.
没错 你无非就是只食腐鸟
That's right. You are nothing more than carrion...
一只啄食无助死亡的贪婪的鸟
a greedy bird pecking at the helpless dead.
我的无助的死亡
My helpless dead.
我是个Valkyrie 我们是骄傲的种族
I am a Valkyrie and we are a proud race.
那你是怎么容许你自己变得如此丑陋
Then how can you let yourself become so... ugly?
凌乱不堪 恶心至极？
So disheveled? So disgusting?
Tamsin 你不过是你自己过往的影子
You're a shadow of your former self, Tamsin.
我的人生快结束了
My lives are ending.
这次真不能回头了
For good this time.
我做错了好多事
And I've made so many mistakes.
我害怕我的灵魂已经
And I fear my soul is...
被诅咒了？
Damned?
是的
Yes.
下地狱？
To hell?
是的
Yes.
你不想变得光彩夺目吗？ 改写你的历史？
Don't you want to be beautiful again? To re-write your path?
拥有新的生命？
To have new life?
太愿意了
More than anything.
我要是能有更多时间 就会弥补一切
If only I had more time... I would do things so differently.
我可以涤荡我的灵魂 消除我的罪恶
I would cleanse my soul.And wipe my sins away.
我能给你你所想要的
I will give you what you desire...
作为交换  我要他的灵魂
but, for payment, I must have his soul.
为什么
Why?
我要以我的血诅咒他
So that I may curse him with the words of my blood.
他的不羁  他的傲慢
For his defiance. For his arrogance.
他以为他能改变血王的法律
For thinking he could change the laws of the King...
他再也不会崛起
so that he will never rise
反抗我的统治
and take arms against my will again.
他的灵魂会永恒的流浪
So that his soul will wander in eternity.
没人会记得他的名字
For no one will remember his name.
没人会记得反抗者Rainer
No one will remember Rainer the defiant.
恩
Uh...
Tammy Tammy你醒醒
Tammy! Tammy wake up!
醒醒 醒醒 我真的错了
Oh wake up. Wake up, I'm so sorry.
对不起 我只是太担心Bo了  Tammy 醒醒
I'm so sorry. I was just worried about Bo, Tammy, wake up!
醒醒啊  快醒醒
Wake up, come on!
你是他吗
Are you him?
你是Rainer吗
Are you Rainer?
我问你话呢
I asked you a question.
你是流浪者吗
Are you the Wanderer?
哦 和我想的略有不同啊
Oh...not really what I was expecting.
我知道你会来找我的
I knew you'd come for me.
英雄所见略同
Yeah, that makes two of us.
嘿 你醒醒啊 我错了
Hey! Wake up!  I'm sorry!
醒醒  求你了 求求你
Wake up! Please, please please...
不管你做什么 绝不要相信Trick
Whatever you do...don't trust Trick.
我们得找到Bo 现在
We have to find Bo. Now.
对 恩
- Yeah, well, we lost her.
她走了  什么？
- What?
她回去火车上了
She's back on the train.
你俩得准备战斗
You two have to arm up...
叫上Hale  叫上Kenzi 叫上Tamsin 尼玛 把Vex也叫上
call Hale, call Kenzi, call Tamsin, hell, call Vex.
Trick 发生了什么事
Trick, what's going on?
我知道谁把Bo带走了 我知道流浪者是谁了
I know who took Bo. I know who the Wanderer is.
他叫Rainer 是我的死敌
His name is Rainer. He's my mortal enemy.
大家好
Hey, guys.
Bo真是谢天谢地
Bo, thank the gods!
嘿你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
恩 对我挺好 从来没这么好过
Yeah, yeah I'm great. Never better actually.
我 恩
I, um...
哇  我知道我为什么当黑暗派了
Whoa.I found out why I agreed to be Dark.
我发现那其实是我的主意
I found out it was my idea actually.
你到底在说什么
What, are you talking about?
对 因此我能不计一切代价
Yeah. It was so I would move Heaven and Earth
回到火车上 去找Rainer
to get back to the train. To Rainer.
自愿
Willingly.
自愿？
Willingly?
所以我才能解除他的诅咒 把他从火车上救出来
So that I could break his curse and free him from the train.
再加那些消失的记忆
And with the whole memory gone thing...
真是让我左右为难
well it became quite a dilemma.
很抱歉让你们经历这些
I'm sorry that I put  all of you through that.
Bo 我不明白  发生什么事了
Bo, I don't understand ...what's happening?
就是他 他就是Rainer
That's him! That's Rainer!
Dyson 别！
Dyson! Don't!
你们都听好了
Just listen. All of you.
我做了这些 因为他不是我的敌人
I did all this... because he is not my enemy,
他也绝不是我父亲
and he is definitely not my father.
他是我的命运
He's my destiny.